http://youtu.be/sxgamL2aCn4
Khang_vgu
You have seen a Logic Analyzer operating in simulation mode.
ta biết về cách hoạt động của bộ phân tích logic trong trình mô phỏng
Today, we're going to show you a real Logic Analyzer.
giờ ta sẽ xem 1 bộ phân tích logic thật
First, we're going to connect signals of our circuit to the Logic Analyzer.
đầu tiên, kết nối các tín hiệu trong mạch vào bộ phân tích logic
So we're going to connect 4 pins for the left motor and 4 more pins
là ta kết nối 4 pin cho motor bên trái
for the right motor and the two pins associated with the sensors.
4 cái cho motor bên phải và 2 pin liên kết với các cảm biến
So we'll connect these 10 pins to the Logic Analyzer.
nghĩa là ta kết nối 10 pin vào bộ phân tích logic
OK.
ok
This is a window showing you real-time recording as the motor is spinning.
đây là cửa sổ ghi lại thời gian thực khi motor quay
Both sensors are off, so they're spinning in the same direction.
cả 2 cảm biến đều tắt, nên các motor quay cùng 1 hướng
These four pins right here, these four signals, represent one motor.
4 pin này, 4 tín hiệu này là cho 1 motor
And there's the 5-- 01, 01.
và đây là 5 - 01, 01
And these four pins are the other motor.
4 pin này cho motor khác
And there's a 5.
ở đây là 5
And so as it turns, we can see that the two motors will go through the pattern
khi motor turn , ta thấy các motor sẽ chuyển qua các mẫu tiếp này
that we've programmed.
là các mẫu ta đã lập trình trước
This is a hardware physical way to test that the system is operational.
đây là cách để kiểm tra phần cứng hoạt động
So Jon, what would happen if I were to press the left bumper
ê John, sẽ như thế nào nếu tôi nhấn nút cảm biến ở bên trái này
sensor that is detecting a wall?
cảm biến xác định tường
You see that what will happen is the speed will drop in half.
bạn thấy đó, tốc độ sẽ giảm nửa
And the one motor will turn in one direction.
1 motor sẽ quay theo 1 hướng
And the other motor will turn in the other direction.
các còn lại quay theo hướng khác
Push the other button.
nhấn nút khác
OK.
ok
Let me try the other one.
để tôi thử nút khác
Again, pushing the right bumper will rotate one wheel in the opposite direction
nhấn tiếp nút bên phải, 1 bánh xe sẽ quay ở hướng ngược lai
and drop the speed in half.
và giảm tốc độ xuống 1 nửa
So we verified the functioning of our logic, both physically by observing it and also by
qua đó, ta sẽ kiểm định chức năng của mạch logic, bằng cách quan sát
monitoring it in a Logic Analyzer.
và giám sát trên bô phân tích logic
One last thing to notice is that the time between steps is exactly
1 thứ khác mà ta quan tâm là thời gian giữa mỗi bước là chính xác 20 ms
20 milliseconds.
20 ms
And this 20 milliseconds was created with the SysTick periodic interrupts.
và 20 ms này được tạo bởi SysTick periodic interrupt